MATTHEW WRIGHT

132 Pleasant Street, Northfield, VT 05663, 8024988274, matt2a.wright@gmail.com

VALUE ADDED

Motivated Cyber Security students with three years of servicing Norwich University's War Room and Forensics Lab with computer troubleshooting. Proven track record for being efficient in maintaining active systems and implementation of new security policies. Possesses strong work ethic and organization skills by actively ensuring work environment is clean and safe for all team members and assisting with training new members on critical office procedures. Expert with computer hardware diagnostics, security and risk assessments, virtual systems administration. Intermediate experience with small team management of 6-10 people, penetrating testing using Kali Linux and network monitoring. Seeking more experience in the area of policy creation and implementation.

EDUCATION

Computer Security - Information Assurance BS Norwich University, Northfield, VT

May 2021

Scholarships & Awards at Norwich University - All requiring above 2.0 GPA & 12 credit hours

- Joseph G. & Ruth R. Sabol Mem. Scholarship
- Peter D. Knowlton Scholarship
- Academic Recognition Award
- Esports Competitor Award

EXPERIENCE

GenCyber Outreach Coordinator

September 2019 - May 2020

Norwich University Center for Cybersecurity and Forensics Education | Northfield, Vermont

- Provided assistance by teaching study strategies and answering questions about taking Access Data's FTK Certifiable Exam for their forensic software.
- Supported other Coordinators with technical support for virtual systems and coordinating appointments with students to help them succeed in the FTK examination.
- Proposed ideas to administrative staff on improving student interaction in an online format and led the implementation of approved suggestions.

Head Administrator

January 2019 - February 2020

Norwich University Center for Cybersecurity and Forensics Education | Northfield, Vermont

- Supervised a small team of 6-10 people.
- Set weekly team goals to ensure technical problems were resolved and teams worked efficiently.
- Penetration testing utilizing the Kali Linux operating system to determine system vulnerabilities on a 3month basis to ensure our systems were secure and followed organization policies.
- Created policies regarding physical and digital access to virtual systems, servers, and user systems, including a timely removal of old accounts and usage of least privilege based upon Norwich Universities' larger policies.
- Assisted Administrators with improving day-to-day operations by cleaning up workspaces and teaching junior administrators on how to complete daily tasks.

- Developed an organization system of hardware and software for the Center to improve awareness
 of current and outgoing inventory for the Director.
- Developed a workflow to improve high-volume time blocks by prioritizing work ticket and organizing computer hardware and tools. This workflow improved overall efficiency and lead to faster recovery times on downed systems.

Senior Administrator

August 2018 - January 2019

Norwich University Center for Cybersecurity and Forensics Education | Northfield, Vermont

- Ensured the Center's effectiveness by fixing CPU and motherboard failures
- Managed firewall rules and actively monitored network traffic with successful software implementation and usage
- Managed hardware resources and accounts for virtual machines on a local server of over 100
 active users.
- Provided hands on training opportunities to junior administrators to increase their skill base whenever they were available.
- Empowered Junior Administrators to solve problems and learn with the 52 physical computers and 4 CISCO servers we operated.
- Motivated employees by making tasks enjoyable via learning and interacting with them and teaching them new things so that they would continuously gain knowledge and enhance their abilities.

Counselor/Teachers Assistant

Summer 2017 - Summer 2018 - Summer 2019

Norwich University - GenCyber | Northfield, Vermont

- Maintained program efficiency by keeping work areas clean, tidy, and free of debris so employees can focus on completing tasks and maintain accurate inventory.
- Provided technical software and hardware support for end users by troubleshooting software issues and determining faulty hardware.
- Trained new team members on average issues students may have and created a friendly environment
 by always being willing to help others. This in turn made the students feel comfortable with talking to
 us and being willing to asking questions.

EXTRACURRICULAR & LEADERSHIP

Captain

September 2018 - December 2020

Norwich University Esports – Siege JV Team | Northfield, Vermont

- Managed a team of 7-8 players.
- Created the team and ran 6 seasons of competitive play where we improved greatly.
- Managed the team's practice and game schedules with regular attendance being recorded.
- Communicated with Captains of other Universities to schedule games and scrimmages.
- Successfully lead 4 members from this team to a promotion onto the varsity team.
- Promoted to Varsity team in January of 2021

Course Driven Experience Norwich University | Northfield, Vermont

September 2018 - May 2021

- Created detailed risk assessment reports on security issues related to both digital and physical mediums to inform clientele on recommended remediations.
- Penetration testing utilizing the Kali Linux operating system to determine system vulnerabilities.